嗨  我是Dan Aminzade  是Android Wear团队的一名攻城狮
Hi, I'm Dan Aminzade, an engineer on the Android Wear team.
如果你制作过安卓APP的话  你可能会困惑如何更新你的APP
If you build Android apps, you may be wondering how to update your app
使它能够更好地在可穿戴设备上工作
to work better on a wearable form factor.
在这个视频里
To give you a better idea of the changes you might want
为了让你更好地了解你可能要做出的改变  我会告诉你
to make, in this talk, I'll tell you
我们是如何更新谷歌自己的APP  使其更好的支持安卓可穿戴设备的
how we updated Google's own apps to better support Android Wear.
我将重点放在四款APP上
I'm going to focus on four apps that
来展示使用Android Wear API开发的不同点  分别是 Gmail
showcase different aspects of the Android Wear API, Gmail,
Hangouts  Camera和Google Maps
Hangouts, Camera and Google Maps.
其中的每个APP展示了
Each of these apps illustrates a different set
Android Wear API的不同方面的特征
of features of the Android Wear API.
让我们从Gmail开始吧
Let's start with Gmail.
Gmail会在你的手机上产生两种类型的通知
Gmail generates two types of notifications on your phone.
一种是是像这样  当你收到一封电子邮件时
A notification like this, when you have one email.
另一种是像这样  当你有多封未读邮件时
And a notification like this, when you have multiple unread emails.
一封电子邮件的通知会包含这封邮件的部分片段
The notification for one email has a snippet of the email,
以及2个操作  归档和回复
and two actions; archive and reply.
不对Gmail做任何的改变
Without changing Gmail at all, the notification
该通知会从手机推送到可穿戴设备上
would be bridged from phone to wearable,
并且会在屏幕上显示为一张卡片
and would show up as a card in the stream.
你可以在卡片上滑动来选择回复或归档
You could swipe on the card to select reply or archive.
问题是回复动作是否能够做的
The problem is that the reply action
像在手机上选择一样
would do exactly what it did when selected on the phone--
让你打开手机里的Gamil APP
it would open up the Gmail app on your phone,
然后输入回复内容
so you could type a response.
所以我们最先想做的
So the first thing we wanted to do
是允许人们说出快速的语音
was to allow people to speak quick voice
来回复他们的手表  使他们可以直接通过手腕
replies to their watch so they can answer emails directly
回复电子邮件
on their wrist.
安卓的通知API现在可以
The Android notification API now lets
给通知动作
you annotate a notification action
添加一个远程输入  它告诉Android Wear
with a remote input, which tells Android Wear that you'd
在执行动作之前  你可能要通过语音收集
like to collect a bit of free form text via speech
一些自由形式的文本
before performing the action.
当我们在Gmail中创建一个通知时
When we build a notification in Gmail,
我们对回复动作附上一个远程输入
we attach a remote input to the reply action.
Android Wear捕获到这个远程输入
Android Wear sees this remote input,
不是立即激活这个动作
and instead of firing the action immediately,
而是首先打开一个转录UI收集说出的回复内容
it first launches a transcription UI to collect a spoken response.
在激活手机上的intent之前
Then it puts the transcribed text into the intent,
将转录文本发送到intent
before firing the intent on the phone.
当Gmail启动并发现这个文本
When Gmail starts up and sees this text,
它会知道需要如何完成回复动作
it knows that it has what it needs to complete the reply
然后继续并发送邮件
action, and it can go ahead and send the email
而不用打开手机上的任何UI
without bringing up any UI on the phone.
所以添加语音回复只需要稍微修改两处代码
So adding voice replies just required two small code changes.
首先  改变回复动作以包含一个远程输入
First, changing the reply action to include a remote input.
接着  修改从这个动作
And second, modifying the activity
接收到的intent的activity
that received the intent from this action,
判断intent是否包含一个文本响应
to see if the intent included a text response.
最酷的是通知体验
What's cool is that the notification experience
在手机上并没有改变
on the phone is unchanged.
如果你选择在手机通知栏中回复通知
If you select the reply action on the phone's notification
Gmail会启动同样的activity
shade, Gmail starts the same activity.
但是由于远程输入不密集
But since the remote input isn't populated,
它通常会显示Compose窗口让你输入一个回复
it displays the Compose window as usual to let you type a response.
现在  我们来看看多个消息通知的情况
Now, let's look at the multiple message notification,
它使用多行收件箱样式
which uses the multi-line inbox style.
在一个可拓展的设计中
Instead of putting a bunch of short lines of text
我们需要每个邮件单独显示一张卡片
onto a single card, we wanted to have one card for each email,
而不是把一堆短行文本挤在一张卡片上
in an expandable stack.
这些大量的通知卡片
These bundles, or stacks of notification cards,
是通知API的一个新特性
are a new feature in the notification API.
不是将所有的电子邮件线程合并在一起
Instead of posting one notification
发送一个通知
with all of the email threads coalesced,
而是我们发布多个通知  每一封电子邮件一个通知
we post multiple notifications-- one per email.
但是所有这些通知都具有相同的group key
But all of these notifications are marked with the same group
以表明他们是相关的
key, indicating that they're related,
然后它们在可穿戴设备上被组合为一个卡片包
and they should be grouped as a card bundle on the Wearable.
现在我们得到了一个不错的卡片集合
Now we get a nice stack of cards,
你可以通过点击包来展开它们
which you can fan out by tapping the bundle,
然后分别阅读每张卡片
and read the cards individually.
注意到在包中的每个卡片
Notice that each of the cards in the bundle
可以有自己的动作
can also have its own actions, so we can now
所以我们可以在这一组中回复或归档单独的邮件
reply to or archive a single email from within the group--
就像我们处理单独的邮件一样
just as we did with a single email.
通知集合还有一个sort key
Notification bundles also have a sort key,
你可以通过设置来控制在包中的卡片的顺序
which you can set to control the ordering of cards within the bundle.
你可以标志包中的一个通知
You can mark one notification in the bundle
作为一个摘要通知
as a summary notification, which is representative
它是整组通知的代表
of the group as a whole.
对于Gmail  我们采用默认的原始收件箱样式通知
For Gmail, we flag the original inbox style notification
作为摘要
as the summary.
摘要通知
The summary notification is displayed
显示在手机通知栏中
on the phone's notification shade.
没有摘要的包是显示在可穿戴设备上的
And the bundle without the summary is displayed on the Wearable.
接下来  让我们看看Hangouts
Next, let's look at Hangouts.
Hangouts消息同样可以自动弥合在可穿戴设备上
Hangouts messages are automatically bridged to the wearable too.
但是我们想要做些细微的改变
But we wanted to make some changes to fine tune
来增强安卓可穿戴设备的体验
the experience for Android Wear devices.
和Gmail一样  我们想要语音回复
As with Gmail, we wanted voice replies.
但是Hangouts的通知是有点不同的
But the Hangouts notifications are a little bit different.
它们没有回复动作
They don't have a reply action, just a content intent that
只有一个content intent打开应用程序  以使你可以输入回复内容
opens up the app, so you can type a response.
这在可穿戴设备上显示为一个手机的Open动作
This shows up as an Open on Phone action on the Wearable.
幸运的是  现在的通知API允许您在手机和可穿戴设备中
Fortunately, the notification API now lets you specify a distinct set
指定不同的动作集合
of actions on phone and Wearable.
手机动作仅仅会显示在手机上
The phone actions will only be displayed on the phone,
同样可穿戴设备的动作只会显示在可穿戴设备上
and the Wearable actions will only be displayed on the Wearable.
这就允许我们添加一个可穿戴设备仅有的回复动作
This allowed us to add a Wearable only reply
包含一个远程输入
action, which includes a remote input without changing
却不改变手机的行为
the phone behavior.
Hangouts 同样使用另一个新的通知功能
Hangouts also uses another new notification feature,
即消息页面
Notification Pages.
我们认为这将很有用  如果在主消息卡片上
We thought it would be useful if you could swipe sideways
滑动侧边栏  你可以在另一个页面
on the main message card to see a second page
看到最近的历史对话记录
with the recent conversation history.
这个不是手机非常必要的
This isn't really necessary on the phone,
因为你可以打开APP去查看历史对话记录
because you can just open the app to see the conversation history.
但是在可穿戴设备上  在回复之前
But on the Wearable, it's nice to get a little extra context
获得额外的上下文是很有必要的
before speaking a response.
为了实现这个功能  我们使用WearableExtentder的AddPage方法
To do this, we use the Add Page method
它允许你在主要的通知上
of Wearable Extender, which allows you to add extra pages of content
添加额外的内容页面
on the primary notification.
我们把chatHistory设置为第二个bigText style的通知
We put the chat history into a second big text style
并将它添加到主通知作为第二页
notification, and add it to the primary notification as a second page.
同样  通知体验在手机上并不会变
Once again, the notification experience on the phone is unchanged.
但是在可穿戴设备上  我们得到了第二页的内容
But on the Wearable, we get the second page of content,
来展示聊天记录
showing the chat history.
这就是Hangouts在可穿戴设备上的一个完整例子
Here's a full example of Hangouts on the wearable.
这是一个图片消息  一页仅仅是一个图片
This is a picture message, with one page for just a photo, one
一页仅仅是聊天历史记录  和一个回复动作
page with the chat history, and a reply action,
来记录一个快速的音频回复
for recording a quick voice reply.
让我们来看Camera
Let's move on to Camera.
我们想为谷歌摄像APP添加一个有趣的功能
We wanted to add a fun little feature to Google's Camera app
这会让你从你的手腕触发快门
that would let you trigger a shutter release from your wrist.
你可能见过具有远程控制功能的高端相机
You've probably seen high end cameras with remote controls,
这里的想法是相同的
and the idea here is the same.
你把你的手机放在三脚架上
You put your phone on a tripod, or maybe you
或是你靠在墙的另一面  或者你让别人帮你拿着相机
lean it against a wall, or you give it to someone to hold.
然后你通过按可移动设备上的按钮来触发照相
And then you capture a photo by tapping a button on your watch.
对于Gmail和Hangouts  仅仅通过使用通知API
With Gmail and Hangouts, we did entirely phone-side
我们完全实现了手机端的集成
integrations, using only the notification APIs.
但对于这个例子
But for this use case, it made sense
制作一个可穿戴设备APP是有意义的
to build a Wearable app for a couple of reasons.
首先  当全屏运行时
First, it wouldn't really make sense for the camera app
他不会对Camera APP投放消息
to post notifications to the phone shade, when
在手机上产生影响
it was already running full screen,
所以我们知道手机设备上的行为和可穿戴设备上的
so we knew that the behavior on the phone and the wearable
是不对称的
had to be asymmetric.
我们也认为  对于这个例子
Also, we thought that for this use case,
通过可穿戴设备快门按钮接管整个屏幕是合适的
it would be appropriate to take over the entire screen of the Wearable
而不是在屏幕上限制
with the shutter button, instead of confining
卡片的按钮功能
the button to a card in the stream.
所以  我们建立了一个简单的应用程序运行在可穿戴设备上
So we built a simple app to run on the Wearable, that
通过谷歌游戏服务来和主要的Camera APP沟通
communicates with the main Camera app, using Google Play services.
当Camera APP准备去拍照的时候
When the Camera app is ready to take a picture,
它将设置一个dataItem
it sets a data item, indicating that it's
表明准备接受远程快门的消息
ready to accept remote shutter messages.
这个数据项是由智能手表上的可穿戴设备APP的一个service来实现读取的
This data item is read by a service within the Wearable app
它上面显示了快门键
on the watch, which displays the shutter button.
按下按钮将发送消息给手机
Tapping the button sends a message back to the phone
来触发快门
to trigger shutter press.
最后  为了预览你刚刚拍摄的照片
Finally, to preview the photo you just took,
手机应用程序创建了一个缩略图
the phone app creates a thumbnail
并将其返回给手表仅作为一个存放数据的物品
and sends it back across to the watch as an asset within a data item.
可穿戴设备读取内容  并全屏预览
The Wearable reads the asset, and displays it full screen for preview.
这就是它最终看起来的效果
Here's what it looks like end to end.
我在手机上打开Camera APP  然后看到一个写有字符串的卡片
I open the Camera app on my phone, and I see a string card.
我可以轻触卡片启动一个
I can tap the card to launch a full screen
具有快门按钮的全屏activity
activity with the shutter button.
我轻敲快门按钮  然后经过倒计时后
I tap the shutter button, and after a count down,
我的手机拍下来一张照片  并且可以在可移动设备上预览
my phone takes a photo, and I see a preview on the Wearable.
不错的自拍
Not a bad selfie.
让我们来看谷歌地图
Let's move on to Google Maps.
在语音导航时
During turn by turn navigation, we
我们想在手腕上显示方向
wanted to show direction prompts on your wrist.
这会在你走路时非常管用
These can be especially useful when you're walking,
当你感到拿着你的手机很尴尬时
since it's awkward holding up your phone,
现在你可以更方便的把手机丢在口袋里
and it could be more convenient to leave it in your pocket,
然后来靠你的手表来展示方向啦
and refer to turn descriptions on your watch.
因为我们想要在可穿戴设备的
Because we wanted fine grained control
布局和方向的表现上
over the layout and the presentation of the directions
获得更加细粒度的控制
displayed on the wearable, we decided
我们决定制作谷歌地图穿戴APP
to build the Google Maps Wear app, that rendered custom drawn
来呈现自定义信息而不是单纯的消息推送
cards as local only notifications.
我们修改了谷歌地图手机应用程序
We modified the Google Maps phone app
来更新对于数据项的描述信息
to update a data item with the description
下一步机动动作图标
and the icon for the next maneuver,
和导航状态信息
and info about the navigation state.
地图穿戴APP监听数据项的变化
The Maps Wear app listens for changes to this data item.
每次改变  它将重新读取新数据
With each change, it reads the new data,
然后更新卡上的数据到到移动设备上
and updates the card on the Wearable.
为了绘制这张卡片
To draw the card, the Wearable app
可穿戴设备APP使用了WearableExtender的新的displayIntent的功能
uses the new display intent feature of Wearable Extender.
你指定一个activity来绘制
You specify an activity to draw the content
通知卡片上的内容
within a notification card.
这可以使你随心所欲的画上你想显示的内容在卡片上
This lets us just draw whatever we wanted on the card,
而不是被标准的通知样式所局限
instead of being constrained to the standard notification styles.
卡片在周围低功率模式下  或是峰值状态下
Cards in ambient low power mode, or in this peaking state,
仍需要使用标准的通知模板
still have to use standard notification templates.
但是当你轻触卡片进入到全屏视图后
But when you swipe the card up into full view,
系统将会改变色调进入自定义视图
the system cross fades the card into a custom view,
由自定义显示activity来绘制
drawn by the custom display activity.
这个有些不爽的是
It's a bit of a bummer that you have
无论是在峰值模式还是环境模式都不得不使用标准样式
to use standard styles in peak mode and in ambient mode,
但安卓穿戴设备引用了一些新的
but Android Wear does introduce some new Wearable
可穿戴设备特定的通知模板  就像大的动作样式
specific notification templates, like big action style
和内容图标样式
and content icon style.
最后一个特性
One last feature.
我们同样也想让你开始一个导航会话
We also wanted to let you start a navigation session
通过一个声音命令  比如导航到donuts公司
by speaking a voice command, like navigate to donuts.
为了实现这个  地图穿戴应用有一个activity
To do this, the Maps Wear app has an activity
它具有一个将导航声音动作过滤的intent filter
with an intent filter for the navigate voice action, which
就像这样来创建一个intent
creates an intent like this.
穿戴式应用收到这个intent
The Wear app receives this intent,
并将一条消息发送给手机上的谷歌地图
and sends a message to Google Maps on the phone that
包含一个目的地与到达方式
contains a destination, and a travel mode.
手机地图应用收到这个消息
The Maps phone app receives this message,
并开始一个导航会话到目的地
and starts a navigation session to the destination.
然后你就可以出发了
And off you go.
这就是我们的Gmail Hangoouts Camera 和谷歌地图
That's how we made Gmail, Hangouts, Camera, and Google
都准备好了为安卓穿戴设备而奋斗
Maps, all ready for Android Wear.
我希望它能给你一个很好的介绍关于
I hope it gave you a good overview of what
你可以在安卓穿戴设备平台上做些什么
you can do on the Android Wear platform.
我希望它能激发你定制自己的应用程序
And I hope it inspires you to customize your own application
来更好的支持可穿戴设备的体验
to support a better wearable experience.